Jon Christie

(919) 368-3369 • fullstack11235@gmail.com • www.jonchristie.net

OBJECTIVE

Coding Instructor for Varsity Tutors and freelance web developer with over 7 years experience in web development following 11 years in education. React and React Native expert with an ongoing drive to learn and utilize technology to improve the lives of others and the world we live in. Active listening, adaptability, communication, confidence, creativity, patience, problem solving, teamwork, time management, humor, and fun are some additional skills I practice, value, and happily share.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

• HTML	• CSS	 Javascript & TypeScript 	Python
FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES, AND	ENVIRONMENTS		·
 React & React Native 	• MaterialUI, Bootstrap, Bulma	 NodeJS 	 MaterialUI
• ThreeJS	• D3	NextJS	TailwindCSS
SYSTEMS, CMS, & DATABASES			
• Git	• CLI	 MySQL 	• HTTP
MongoDB	• REST	• APIs	 Amazon Web Services
TESTING			
 React Testing Library 	• Jest	Mocha	
OTHER SOFTWARE + SKILLS			
• SEO	 Quantitative analysis 	 Responsive Web Design 	 Functional Programming
 Object Oriented Programming 	Adobe CS	• Figma	Unity 3D

• Blender PROJECTS

Super Pantry Buddy, 2020

- Live Site: https://superpantrybuddy.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/mathcodes/SuperPantryBuddy

Logic Pro X

- Technology: React, React ContextMongoDB, Node, ORM, Express, OAuth, Jest, Bulma, Figma
- **Description:** MERN stack- Responsive, customizable user experience to find and save recipes. I personally implemented authhorization, State, and testing. Future development includes improving UI and utilizing more data from the API.

Audio Production

A Python Log, 2021

- Live Site: https://jonspythonlog.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/mathcodes/PythonLog/
- Technology: Python, CSS, HTML, JS, Replit, Django, Tkinter, JSON, Illustrator
- **Description:** A full stack blog using Python in the backend. Users post, share, and delete content using HTTP Requests and CRUD conventions. A mobile-friendly design adds functionality with a responsive UI.

Gladis & Co., 2022-current

- Live Site: http://www.gladisandco.com/
- Technology: JS, HTML, CSS, WordPress
- **Description:** By far the highest demanding gig I've had that put my JS and CSS skills to the test. For reasons out of my control, I was tasked with restyling a website with no access to the root directory nor the plug-in used in WordPress to build the site originally. Both GoDaddy and even WordPress customer service were baffled and essentially gave up, which makes me proud and my client happy, that I was able to fix all the issues using advanced JS and CSS techniques to either override existing code or utilize server-side rendering to handle dynamic aspects of the site.

Jon Christie

(919) 368-3369 • fullstack11235@gmail.com • www.jonchristie.net

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Varsity Tutors – Coding Instructor

Remote 2021 – present

- Maintained a 100% success rate with both student retention and feedback, all 5/5 and written by students of all ages each week, verifying the quality of my services and knowledge of the material
- Led presentations to up to 100 listeners at a time covering HTML, JS, CSS, Express, Node, MongoDB, React while fielding questions from the viewers with a cumulative 94% successful review rating.
- Created and implemented various lessons plans covering several different learning strategies for mastering code amounting to 20-30 hours of work per week on top of research, projects, and tutoring sessions
- Inspired and motivated students using my knowledge and love for over 20 in-demand coding languages and technologies
 including Javascript, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Python, OOP, React, AWS Cloud Services, Node, Express, TypeScript, Data
 Structures and Algorithms

Pivotous - Reputation Manager / Web Developer

Remote 2020 - 2021

- Organized and oversaw a team of 11 Technical Assistants by training them on software to track and monitor progress
 using data analytics and up-to-date SEO tactics
- Enhanced competitive analysis using CHAIN and C&RT models to optimize clients' ROI effectively by more than 23%.
- Monitored, restored, and enhanced software updates using marketing software to serve clients at scale
- Expedited and refined marketing strategies using customized software to increase clientele by an average of 178.8%
- Managed team of 30+ successful WPP Brand Account Managers, Media Negotiators and Promotions Specialists

TE21, Inc - EdTech Developer

Durham, NC 2016 - 2018

- Introduced and implemented Python, MathML, LaTeX, HTML, CSS, and JS for entire company's 5-person curricular teams to increase the rate of digitizing 80,000 test items by 7.2 times the original rate to integrate our items into the new Certica platform while maintaining mobile-responsive items.
- Introduced a new industry-wide EdTech feature: customizable test items by state standards while providing an easy-to-use item creator for teachers to create their own items that mirror the End-Of-Course testing functionality.
- Collaborated with Certica techs and formed a team to execute the merging of a total of more than 220,000 test items, each an object with over 50 parameters utilized to implement entity resolution, Machine Learning, and data matching processes to sort and parse the items as needed.

PACE Academy High School, Mathematics Teacher

Carrboro, NC 2006 - 2016

- Increased the Math Department's EOC score from 0% to 100% first year, "Teacher of the Year" 2006-2007
- Managed the Math Department all 8 years and met every budget while bringing technology to my students' daily exercises to maintain a career-long passing rate of 94.3%.
- Adapted to a new environment as a leader quickly and developed strong relationships with co-workers and students
 alike, forming a leadership role which led to years of producing and executing school-wide events, projects, competitions,
 field trips, fund-raisers, and community-based development and events.

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Full-Stack Certificate Program

Web Developer Certificate – Durham Tech, IT Web Developer Certificate

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, BA Mathematics

2001 – 2005